Guide to the Michael Letwin Papers TAM 464
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subject Files, 2010 Accession, 1978-2007; 29 Linear Feet
  - New York City Police Department, undated; 10 Linear Feet
    - New York City Police Department 10, 1983 - 2001 (Box 32)
      Contains: Allan Cameroon, 2005; Shooting by year; Tysheen Bourne and Thomas Boyland, 2000; Reynaldo Colon, 2000; Malcolm Ferguson, 2000; Carmen Valentine, 2000; Andre Austin, 9/18/1999; Gary Busch, 8/30/1999; Larry Cobb, 8/18/99; Stanton Crew, 1999; Walter Hickey, 2/23/1999; Dantae Johnson, 5/26/1999; Charles Stevens, 4/6/1999; Robert Striker, 8/9/1999; Richard Watson, 9/1/1999; Dexter Brown, 1998; Sean Kelly, 9/31/1998; Michael Jones, 1998; Antonio Reid, 6/14/1998; Felix River, 1/1983; Steven Service, 2/27/1998; Jason Rodriguez, 1995; Anthony Rosario, 1/12/95; Argencio, 1/1994; Desmond Robinson, 8/22/1994; Kenneth Cook, 1993; Aurea Bonnie Vargas, 1/29/1993; Earl Black, 5/27/1992; Robert Cabeza, 1992; Jacques Camille, 4/9/1992; Jose Garcia, 7/3/1992; Douglas Orfaly, 3/3/1992; P.O. Derwin Pannell, 11/17/1992; Ardel Amos, 8/25/1991; David Coho, 3/1/1990; Jose Cruz, 12/7/1990; Jose Luis Lebron, 2/1/1990; Luis Liranzo, 1/27/1990; Patrick Bailey, 10/31/1997; Reginald Bannerman, 12/1997; Kevin Cedeno, 4/1997; Donald Davidson, 3/1997; Rodney Dilbert, 1997; William Whitfield, 12/1997; Charles Campbell, 10/1996; Nathaniel Levi Gaines, 7/1996; Gayle Hoffman, 3/1996; Henry Phelan, 1/1996; Thompkins Square Park [riot], 1988
  - Racism, undated; 1 Linear Feet (1 box)
    - Racism, 1980 - 2002 (Box 33)
      Contains: Atlanta murders - Wayne Williams; Greensboro, NC murders, 1979; Latinos, immigration; Klan; Attica Prison (NYS); Martin Luther King; Muslims; Malcolm X; Political prisoners, misc.; Repression, US; MOVE; Mumia Abu Jamal
  - Racist Violence (Box 34)
    - Racist Violence, 1980 - 1989 (Box 34)
      Contains: Central Park jogger 4/89; Bernard Goetz, 1984; Yusef Hawkins, 1989; Howard Beach, 1986; 1980-1989; Willie Turks, June 1982; Crown Heights (Bklyn, NY)
- Series III: Subject Files, 2018 Accession, 1967-2010; 7 Linear Feet 7 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of printed email correspondence, memorandum, committee reports and research materials such as news articles and other literature documenting Letwin's involvement with Association of Legal Aid Attorneys (ALAA) and Legal Aid Society (LAS). Boxes 35 and 36 chronicle the history of ALAA from 1967 to the late 2000s. Boxes 37 to 39 document Letwin's tenure as President of the ALAA (1990-2002). Boxes 40 and 41 reflect Letwin's continued inolvement with the ALAA and LAS in the 2000s.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to the materials in Boxes 35 through 38 is open to research without restriction. Access to the files in Boxes 39 through 41 is restricted until January 1, 2048.
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys: History of, 1967-2001 (Box 35, Folder 1-29, Box 36, Folder 1-18)
  - Affirmative Action at Legal Aid Society, 1989-1993 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Affirmative Action: General (Not ALAA/LAS), 1997-2000 (Box 37, Folder 3-6)
  - Election (Union) Law, 2002-2003 (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys History Project, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 9-11)
  - Letwin, Michael at Association of Legal Aid Attorneys / Miscellaneous, 1989-2002 (Box 37, Folder 12-19)
  - Police Abuse and Justice, 1987-2000 (Box 37, Folder 20-28)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys Materials, 1982-2003 (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
  - TWU Local 100 1999 Strike and City Workers 2000 Coalition, 1995-2004 (Box 38, Folder 7-11)
  - Political Action, 1989-2003 (Box 38, Folder 12-14)
  - 1994 Strike, 1981-2006 (Box 38, Folder 15-20)
  - Training, for Delegates, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys: Materials for Union Representative Training, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 22-26)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys: Miscellaneous, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Affirmative Action (Restricted), 1990-2001 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
    Access to Box 39 is restricted until 2048.
  - Diallo Email War (Restricted), 2000 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Union Election (Restricted), 1999 (Box 39, Folder 5-6)
  - War and Free Speech at Legal Aid Society / Association of Legal Aid Attorneys (Restricted), 1998-2003 (Box 39, Folder 7-12)
  - Miscellaneous (Restricted), 2000 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Union Election (Restricted), 2002 (Box 39, Folder 14-16)
  - Rogers, Jim: Miscellaneous (Restricted), 1997-2001 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Access to Box 40 is restricted until 2048.
  - Union Election (Restricted), 2002 (Box 40, Folder 2-4)
  - War and Free Speech at Association of Legal Aid Attorneys (Restricted), 2003-2010 (Box 40, Folder 5-14)
  - UAW: Trial Committee (Restricted), undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Terry v. Alman (Restricted), 2004 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys (Restricted), 2003 (Box 40, Folder 17-18)
  - Integrated Service Model (Restricted), 2003 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys (Restricted), 2004-2008 (Box 41, Folder 1-14)